A Guide to the American Women Authors Collection 1847-1949, 1970
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
American Women Authors Collection 1847-1949, 1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4656-a
This collection consists of 57 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from the Swann Galleries on 1982 March 23.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 57 items from 47 women authors, chiefly American, 1847-1949, 1970. Most are represented by social notes and brief replies to queries. Several are addressed to Kate Douglas (Smith) Wiggin. Of interest is a letter from Ella Wheeler Wilcox mentioning Jack London and describing her efforts to contact her deceased husband through mediums. Manuscripts include a tribute to Edward Everett Hale by Julia Caroline (Ripley) Dorr, The Lover by Theodosia (Pickering) Garrison, an untitled verse by Sarah Jane (Clarke) Lippincott "Grace Greenwood," and several quotations. There is also a signed photograph of Faith Baldwin and an engraving of Lydia Huntley Sigourney.
Contents List
- Allen, Elizabeth Akers, to editor at Atlantic, signed "Florence Percy" 1858 Jul 14, ALS
  1 p.
- Austin, Jane Goodwin, to Miss Dickinson 1889 Oct 10, ALS
  3 pp.
- Austin, Mary H., to Elizabeth S. Lowry 1913 Mar 3, ALS
- Bacon, Josephine Daskam, to Kate Riggs 1910 Mar 3, ALS
  2 pp.
- Bacon, Josephine Daskam, to Mr. Chapman 1933 Jun 24, ALS
- Barrus, Clara, to Chas. N. Elliot 1921 Dec 30, ALS
- Branch, Mary L.B. to Mr. Griffith n.d., ANS
- Cooke, Grace MacGowan to Mr. Baker 1913 Apr 28, TLS
- Cuthrell, Fatih (Baldwin) -- printed article, "Yuletide is not Always So Merry," autographed; photo of Baldwin, autographed 1949, n.d., TMsS
- Deland, Margaret to Mrs. Riggs 1906 Sep 6, ALS
- Deland, Margaret to Mrs. Perry n.d., ALS
- Dickinson, Anna Elizabeth to [?] 1872 Aug 27, ALS
- Door, Julia Caroline Ripley -- tribute in honor of Dr. Edward Everett Hale's eightieth anniversary, requested by The Writer1902, AMsS
- Earle, Alice Morse to Miss Olcott n.d., ALS
- Follen, Eliza Lee Cabot to "My dear friend" 1847 Jan 7, ALS
- Foote, Mary Hallock to [?] n.d., ALS
- Fuller, Margaret to Knickerbocker Publishing Co. 1902 Feb 3, ALS
- Garrison, Theodosia Pickering -- poem entitled "The Lover" n.d., TMsS
- Hall, Mrs. [Anna Maria] to Sir George 1852 Apr 27, ALS
  4 pp.
- Harper, Olive to Mr. Marshall 1892 Feb 23, ALS
- Harraden, Beatrice to [Kate Douglas] Riggs [?] Mar 14, ALS
- Harrison, Constance Cary to [Kate Douglass] Riggs [?] Monday, ALS
- Holmes, Mary Jane to Mr. H. [J.] Allen 188[7], APCS
- Hopkins, Margaret Briscoe to Miss Whitney n.d., ALS
- Howe, Julia Ward to Miss Hilliard [?] Mar 6, ALS
- Lamb, Martha Joan Reade, to Mrs. Langford 1890 Jun 23, ALS
- 1899 1890 Jun 23, ALS
- Leslie, Eliza to [?] 1899 May 21, ALS
- LeVert, Octavia W., to "My valued friend" 1871 Aug 16, ALS
- Lewis, Kate to Mrs. Hir[sh?] [?] Dec 26, ALS
- Lippincott, Sara Jane to [?], signed by "Grace Greenwood" n.d., ANS
- Lippincott, Sara Jane, untitled verse signed by "Grace Greenwood" n.d., AMsS
- Longfellow, Alice M., to Mr. F.H. Green 1927 Feb 16, ALS
- Longfellow, Alice M., to Mr. Allen [?] Nov 11, ALS
- Magruder, Julia -- quotation, signed 1898 Sep 16, AMsS
- Prentiss, Elizabeth to Mrs. Greeley 1870 Oct 3, ALS
- Proctor, Edna Dean to "My dear cousin" [?] May 28, ALS
- Proctor, Edna Dean to Mr. Marcus [?] Jul 24, ALS
- Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt to Dr. Green 1920 Mar 17, ALS
- Rollins, Alice to Mrs. Stedman [?] Nov 10, ALS
- Ruenzler, Adele to Mr. Gable 1912 May 19, ALS
- Sanborn, Kate to [?], ANS
- Sanborn, Kate to Mr. Graff [?] Feb 19, ALS
- Seawell, Molly Elliot to [?] 1901 May 2, ALS
- Seawell, Molly Elliot to [?] n.d., ALS
- Sigourney, Lydia H. to "Rev'd and dear Sir" with print 1864 Mar 21, ALS
  3 p.
- Somerset, Isabel to Mrs. Holmes 1902 Jul 24, TLS
- Stockton, Louise to [?] 1913, ANS
- Stokes, Margaret to Mr. Appleton 1876 Aug 10, ALS
- Trafton, Adeline to Mr. [O.] R. Dorlan 1873 Feb 18, ALS
- Ward, Mary Alden to "Dear Madame" [?] Mar 26, ALS
- Whiting, Lilian to Little, Brown, and Co. 1913 Mar 16, ALS
- Whitney, Phyllis A. to Mrs. Moody 1970 Nov 9, TLS
- Whitney, Phyllis A. to Mr. Carter 1971 Jun 1, TLS
- Wiggin, Kate Douglas to [?] -- quotation from Bud's Christmas Carol n.d., ANS
- Wilcox, Ella Wheeler to Miss Carter 1916 Nov 23, ALS